Frank L. Wilcox papers, Inclusive: 1923-1966, undated, Bulk: 1941-1946
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Frank L. Wilcox papers
Inclusive: 1923-1966, undated, Bulk: 1941-1946
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3854
Wilcox, Frank L., 1896 - 1977
This collection consists of eight document boxes.
The Frank L. Wilcox papers contain the personal and professional materials of Frank Wilcox, a former mayor of Waco and the son-in-law of Pat Neff.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Frank L. Wilcox, the son of Edward and Fannie Wilcox, was born on 1896 June 12 in Alva, Oklahoma. He graduated from Norman High School and went on to attend the University of Oklahoma where he studied engineering from 1913 to 1914.
In 1915, Wilcox moved to Waco, Texas. After a few years of working at odd jobs, Wilcox chose accounting as the career he would pursue. In 1923, he earned his Certified Public Accountant (CPA) license, becoming the first Waco citizen to do so via examination. For eleven years (1929-1939), Wilcox served as the secretary, and eventually chairman, of the Texas State Board of Public Accountants.
In the midst of his career pursuits, Wilcox married Hallie Maude Neff, the daughter of former Texas Governor and Baylor University President Pat Neff. The couple had no children, but were socially active throughout their forty-four year marriage. Hallie’s personal papers also reside at The Texas Collection.
For approximately fifty years, Wilcox continued his success as an accountant. From 1940 until his death, Wilcox was the Director of the Pioneer Savings Association. Upon the United States’ entry into World War II, Wilcox became an auditor for various ship building companies employed by the United States Navy. In 1949, Wilcox was elected President of the Texas Society of CPAs. A year later, he became the Vice President of the American Institute of CPAs.
In addition to his professional accomplishments, Wilcox was also deeply involved in Waco community life. In the late 1930s, Wilcox was the first secretary-treasurer of the Hedonia Club, an organization which celebrated the young women of Waco and their “coming of age” through balls and pageants. From 1945 to 1946, Wilcox served as the Mayor of Waco. At other times in his life, Wilcox was the President of the Waco Symphony Society, President of the Farm and Ranch Club, and Director of the Waco Housing Authority.
Wilcox passed away on 1977 July 30 at the age of 81. He was buried in Oakwood Cemetery in Waco.
Scope and Content
The Frank L. Wilcox papers contain the professional and personal materials of Frank Wilcox, an accountant and former Mayor of Waco. The chronology of the materials span from 1923 to 1966, but the bulk of the materials originated during Wilcox's experiences as an auditor for the Navy during World War II as well as his tenure as mayor.
Series I. Correspondence is the largest series in the collection. Letters pertaining to Wilcox's civic involvement are prominent. Series II. Financial Documents contains audits and reports for the U.S. Navy as well as tax forms pertaining to land owned by Wilcox's father-in-law, Pat Neff. Legal documents, which comprise the third and smallest series in the collection, describe a court case between Pat Neff and C.H. Wright. The final series is comprised of speeches and articles composed by Wilcox dealing primarily with Waco financial matters.
Arrangement
Prior to processing, the Frank L. Wilcox papers were housed in one banker box. The folders, while well organized, were over-stuffed. Prior to 2013 April, there was no comprehensive inventory.
The former folder titles were implemented in the new organizational scheme. The Frank L. Wilcox papers are now arranged into four series: I. Correspondence, II. Financial Documents, III. Legal Documents, and IV. Literary Productions.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3854. Acquired 1978-02-10
Related Resources
Items in related collections
Pat M. Neff collection, Inclusive: 1847-1952, Bulk: 1920-1947
Hallie Maude Neff Wilcox
Related references
Bailey, Scott. “Frank L. Wilcox: Active Accountant.” Frank L. Wilcox: Term Papers, [vertical file], The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
“City of Waco: Mayor and Council.” City of Waco. Accessed 2013 April 30.
“Frank Wilcox Dies; Former Waco Mayor, CPA.” Waco Tribune Herald. 1977 July 31.
“Hedonia Club.” Hedonia Club. Accessed 2013 April 30.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Neff, Pat Morris, 1871-1952.; Wilcox, Frank L.
Subjects
Accountants -- Texas -- History.; Mayors -- Texas -- Waco.; World War, 1939-1945.
Genres
Articles.; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Speeches.
- Correspondence, 1923-1964, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains personal and professional correspondence both to and from Frank Wilcox. The folder titles, which have been carried over from the collection's initial arrangement, reveal the topics of the correspondence. These include Wilcox's involvement with the city of Waco and the Hedonia Club, various newsletters that he wrote concerning the war effort, and personal letters. The series is in average condition.
  - City of Waco, 1945 April-May (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - City of Waco, 1945 June 8-13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - City of Waco, 1945 June 14-18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - City of Waco, 1945 June 23-30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - City of Waco, 1945 July 2-10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - City of Waco, 1945 July 12-19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - City of Waco, 1945 July 20-23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - City of Waco, 1945 July 24-August 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - City of Waco, 1945 August 4-9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - City of Waco, 1945 August 13-21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - City of Waco, 1945 August 22-September 3 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - City of Waco (1 of 3), 1945 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - City of Waco (2 of 3), 1945 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - City of Waco (3 of 3), 1945 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - City of Waco, 1945 September 4-11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - City of Waco, 1945 September 12-19 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - City of Waco, 1945 September 22-27 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - City of Waco, 1945 September 28-October 8 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - City of Waco, 1945 October 9-11 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - City of Waco, 1945 October 12-17 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - City of Waco, 1945 October 22-23 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - City of Waco, 1945 October 24-November 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - City of Waco, 1945 November 6-8 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - City of Waco, 1945 November 8 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - City of Waco, 1945 November 9-12 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - City of Waco, 1945 November 13-20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - City of Waco, 1945 November 20-23 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - City of Waco, 1945 November 24-26 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - City of Waco, 1945 November 27-December 4 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - City of Waco, 1945 December 5-18 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - City of Waco, 1945 December 19-1946 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - City of Waco, 1946 January 8-30 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - City of Waco, 1946 February (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - City of Waco, 1946 March-April (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - City of Waco (1 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - City of Waco (2 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - City of Waco (3 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - City of Waco (4 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - City of Waco (5 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - City of Waco (6 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - City of Waco (7 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - City of Waco (8 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - City of Waco (9 of 9), circa 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hedonia Club, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hedonia Club, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hedonia Club, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Military Bulletins, 1942-1943 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Military Bulletins, 1943 April 18-June 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Military Bulletins, 1943 June 4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Military Bulletins, 1943 June 5-July (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Military Bulletins, 1943 August 21 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Military Bulletins, 1943 August 21-September (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Military Bulletins, 1943 October-December (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Military Bulletins, 1944 January-March (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Military Bulletins, 1944 June-October (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Military Bulletins, circa 1941-1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1923-1939 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1941-1943 May (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1943 June-October 5 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox (1 of 2), 1943 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox (2 of 2), 1943 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1943 November-1944 June (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1944 July-September (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1945 February-March (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1945 July-October (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1945 November-1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1954-1955 May (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1955 July-1957 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1959-1962 March (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1962 May-August (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox, 1962 September-1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox (1 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox (2 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Personal: Frank Wilcox (3 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Financial Documents, 1932-1950, undated; 2
  This series contains financial documents pertaining to Frank Wilcox and his father-in-law Pat Neff. There are two prominent issues represented in this series: tax documents for Pat Neff's farms and materials from Wilcox's time as an auditor for the United States Navy. The materials are in average condition.
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes, 1932-1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (1 of 2), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (2 of 2), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (1 of 2), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (2 of 2), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (1 of 2), 1948 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (2 of 2), 1948 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (1 of 4), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (2 of 4), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (3 of 4), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes (4 of 4), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - General: Pat Neff: Farm Taxes, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1941 October-November 24 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1941 November 29-December (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 March-April (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 May-June 9 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 June 9-12 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 June 12-22 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 June 23-August 10 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 August 11-October 9 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 October 20-28 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1942 December (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1943 January-July (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1943 August-November (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox, 1943 December-1944 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox (1 of 2), circa 1941-1945 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - General: U.S. Navy: Frank Wilcox (2 of 2), circa 1941-1945 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1941 February-June (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1941 September-October (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1941November (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1941 December 4-12 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1941 December 13 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1941 December 16-23 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1941 December 24-1942 January (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, 1942 February-March (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Audit: U.S. Navy: Ingalls Shipbuilding Corporation, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Legal Documents, 1943-1949; 3
  This series contains legal documents and correspondence pertaining to a lawsuit between Pat Neff and C.H. Wright that stretched through much of the 1940s. The materials are in average condition.
  - Pat Neff vs. Wright et al. (1 of 2), 1943-1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pat Neff vs. Wright et al. (2 of 2), 1943-1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Literary Productions, 1945-1966, undated; 4
  This series contains speeches made by Frank Wilcox as well as articles that he composed concerning the state of Waco's finances during his time as mayor (1945-1946). The materials are in average condition.
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: “This is the Problem” Series: “What is Waco Worth?”, 1945 September 30 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: “This is the Problem” Series: “Are We Pinching Pennies?”, 1945 October 7 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: “This is the Problem” Series: “Why Extend the City Limits?”, 1945 October 14 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: “This is the Problem” Series: “Is Waco Inc. a Little Business?”, 1945 October 21 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: “This is the Problem” Series: “A Fable”, 1945 October 28 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: Waco Finances: “What About Post-War Plans?”, 1945 April 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: Waco Finances: “Where Waco Gets Its Money”, circa 1945 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: Waco Finances: “Where Waco Spends Its Money”, 1945 March 29 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Article: Frank Wilcox: Waco Finances: “Which Way Waco?”, circa 1945 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1956 January-March (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1956 June (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1956 August-October (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1958-1962 January (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1962 May-1963 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox (1 of 7), undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox (2 of 7), undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox (3 of 7), undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox (4 of 7), undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox (5 of 7), undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox (6 of 7), undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Speeches: Frank Wilcox (7 of 7), undated (Box 8, Folder 16)